Guide to the Prince William Cultural Arts Federation records, 1979-1990s
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
Prince William Cultural Arts Federation papers
1979-1990s
C0297
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
2.25 linear feet (5 boxes)
The Prince William Cultural Arts Federation records include correspondence, administrative documents, and event information.
Prince William Cultural Arts Federation.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Prince William County Library in November and December 2016.
Historical Information
The Prince William Cultural Arts Federation was a non-profit organization that ended in 1993 after thirteen years of promoting and funding arts groups in Prince William County. They provided support and raised awareness for other visual and performance arts organizations in the community by establishing cultural centers, advocating for arts in public education, sought sources of funding for the arts, and encouraging attendance at all arts events.
Scope and Content
The Prince William Cultural Arts Federation records include correspondence, position descriptions and applications, memos, administrative documents, budget information and other documents dating from 1979 until the early 1990s when the CAF disbanded.
Arrangement
Documents in this collection are arranged by subject.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center holds several other notable collections related to performing arts in Virginia such as the Prince William Symphony Orchestra records.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Prince William County (Va.)
Subjects:
Nonprofit organizations--Virginia.; Performing arts.
Contents List
- Prince William Cultural Arts Federation, 1979-1990s
  - Administrative Files, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ben Lomond Manor House, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters and Administrative Files, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Files, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Files, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Files and Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Floppy Disks, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Files and Articles, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A Day in the Arts Program, May 8, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Files, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Prince George's Magazine, Summer 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stage Door Sales Records, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CAF File-Prince William County, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CAF Correspondence, Jul.- Dec. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Information on Surveys, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CAF Correspondence, Jul.- Dec. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CAF Correspondence, Jan.- Jun. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership (old), 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bulk Mailing, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Performing Arts Center Rockville, MD, circa 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Plan-VA Commission for the Arts, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prince George's Arts Information, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Prince George's Magazine Summer 1983, Administrative Files and Articles, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County Council of the Arts, Administration Files and Articles, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Prince George's Arts; Flyers, Events and Newspapers, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CAF Publicity, Articles, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Survey, September 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Voluntary Action Center, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Youth" Questionnaire, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Calendar of Events, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grants/Fund Requests, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Research Publicity Grant, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - IBM Club re. Ticket Sales, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CAF Insurance, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Job Descriptions, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - P.A. Leisure Lines, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mailing List Chamber of Commerce, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Management Workshops CAF Attendance, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Maps DCCC Kenney's, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership in CAF, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Certificates, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Resumes- Membership Development, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mileage Reimbursement Forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Multimedia Exhibit, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Nominating Committee Information, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fund Raising Ideas, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Brochure Ideas/Surveys, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - CAF Board, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bulk Mailing Receipts, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Blank Certificates of Appreciation, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Contracts, October 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Administrative and Funding Information; Articles, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Prince William County Park Authority Information and Site Review, March 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cultural Alliance, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Executive Director Job Descriptions and Applications, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Fairfax County Council of the Arts Brochure's, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Feasibility Study Completed under Grant by Deanna Shoob, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - CAF Files, Newsletter Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Spring Festival of Arts, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - CAF Board Minutes, Jan.- Dec. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Budget Presentation to Park Authority Building; President Kenney's Speech, March 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ConTelVision Information, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1981 Annual Meeting (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, Aug.- Dec. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - FY82 Budgets, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Final Report from Park Authority for FY82 Payments, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Financial Statements, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Forms, Correspondence and Administrative Files, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)